[ALARM BLARING]
[INMATES INDISTINCTLY YELLING AND GRUNTING]
[IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
[SCREAMS AND GROANS]
[COUGHING]
[CONTINUES COUGHING]
[GUARDS INDISTINCTLY YELLING AND DOGS BARKING]
[GUARDS CONTINUE YELLING INDISTINCTLY]
CHOW: Motherfuckers!
王八蛋們！
Fuck.
幹
[GRUNTING]
[SPLASHING]
[RUMBLING]
Fuck!
幹
[LAUGHING]
[CONTINUES LAUGHING]
We're almost home, buddy!
哥們兒，咱快到家了！
[CAR HORN HONKING]
ALAN: Whoo!
喔！
Whoo!
Hey.
My name's Alan and I bought a giraffe!
哥叫艾倫，哥有長頸鹿！
He's all mine!
它是哥的！
He's super friendly!
它很屌！
[HOWLING]
[BLEATING]
WOMAN: Oh, wow.
哇塞
Look at the giraffe.
看那頭長頸鹿
GIRL: Oh, my God. Where do you think it's going?
天哪，它要去哪？
Whoo!
喔！
Oh, my life is great! I have a wonderful life!
我的生活屌爆了！
I have a wonderful life!
屌爆了！
[GRUNTS]
[FAMILY SCREAMING]
[TRUCK HORN HONKING AND TIRES SCREECHING]
[CAR ALARM BLARING]
Yes, sir. Absolutely, I will. Thank you so much. No, of course.
是的，先生。我一定會的。太謝謝您了。當然，當然。
No, no. And again, I'm so sorry.
不是吧，又這樣，我很抱歉
That was the mayor, Alan.
艾倫，市長剛剛打來
It was an accident.
這是個意外
You said you'd always love me no matter what I did.
你說過不管我做什麼你都會愛我的
I know and I do. You're my best friend. But, Alan, why would you buy a giraffe?
我愛你。你是我最好的朋友。但是，你買長頸鹿幹嘛？艾倫。
I've always wanted one.
我一直想要一頭
I could feed him from my tree house.
我可以拿我的樹屋喂它
Besides, they remind me a lot of myself.
而且，我覺得我很像它
In what way?
怎麼像了？
They're majestic, pensive and tall.
像它一樣高貴冷豔有內涵
- Pensive? ALAN: - Yeah.
-有內涵？-沒錯
- Where'd you learn that word? - "Words With Friends."
-你從哪學的這個詞？-Words with Friends（Zynga出品的小遊戲）
- What friends, Alan? - You can set it on random.
-什麼朋友？-系統隨機分配的
[GROANS]
Alan, aside from the fact that you shut down a freeway...
拋開這個不說，艾倫，你害的一條高速公路都關了
...you murdered a wild animal. It's national news.
還殺了一頭野生動物-這可是大新聞
You don't want to know the checks I had to write to fix this.
你根本不知道我花了多少錢來擺平這件事
Oh, please. We're rich.
拜託，我們很有錢
We are not anything, Alan.
有錢就屌咩？艾倫
I am well-off. You are my 40-year-old son...
我是有錢，都把你養到40歲了
Forty-two. I'm 42!
42，我42歲了！
...42-year-old son who still lives at home.
42歲還住在家裡
You are to go back on your medication or I'm cutting you off.
你要繼續接受治療了，否則我就不給你錢花了
You're bluffing. When's dinner?
別鬧了，什麼時候吃晚飯？
Your mother and I can't take this anymore!
我和你媽都不能忍了！
- Well, you might have to. SID: - I can't do it!
-好把，你或許應該去治療下-我不要！
I cannot do this!
我不要這樣！
[INAUDIBLE DIALOGUE]
BILLY JOEL (SINGING OVER HEADPHONES): I don't care what you say anymore
This is my life
Go ahead with your own life Leave me alone
CHORUS (SINGING): Keep it to yourself It's my life
LINDA: Alan! Alan!
ALAN (SINGING): Ave
Maria
[CONTINUES SINGING "AVE MARIA"]
My God, he's got the voice of an angel.
天啊，他唱的真好聽
It's breathtaking.
讓人透不過氣來
Ave
Maria
[CLEARS THROAT]
I can't believe my daddy is dead.
我不敢相信我爸死了
[FEEDBACK OVER MICROPHONE]
I can think of so many people I would rather have died first.
我想起了許多可以死在他之前的人
Like my mother.
譬如說我媽
As many of you know...
正如你們所知
...my father and I were extremely close.
我爸和我很要好
He was my life partner.
他是我生活的伴侶
He would often tell me, almost on a daily basis...
像每日必修的功課一樣，他經常跟我說
...that I was his favorite child.
我是他最愛的孩子
I'll always remember the last words he said to me:
我會永遠記得他跟我說的最後一句話
"I'm proud of you, Alan."
我為你驕傲，艾倫
"Never change."
一直都是
Well...
嗯…
...I heard you loud and clear, Daddy.
爸，我聽見了
I will never change.
我不會變了
Never, ever.
永遠不會
[FEEDBACK OVER MICROPHONE]
Oh, Mom.
天啊
Go ahead, chief.
你繼續吧
Sid Garner was a beloved husband...
希德·加納是位好丈夫
[SHUTTER CLICKS]
...father and neighbor.
好父親和好鄰居
Wow, rough day.
真是難過的一天
- Yeah, how's Tracy doing? - Not great.
-沒錯，崔西最近好嗎？-不怎麼好
Her mother's totally on the edge, and if all this weren't enough...
她媽處在崩潰邊緣
...apparently Alan's been off his meds for almost six months.
艾倫放棄治療快半年了
Oh, boy.
天啊
Yeah, it has not been pretty.
這可不太好
- Then there's the whole fucking giraffe thing. - I thought that was pretty funny.
-然後出了長頸鹿那碼子事-我倒覺得挺有趣的
- What? - Come on. He killed a giraffe.
-什麼？-拜託，他殺了一頭長頸鹿
Who gives a fuck?
誰他媽的在乎？
You know, I wasn't gonna say anything, but Alan's been stopping by my office lately.
我不打算說什麼，但是艾倫最近經常來我的診所
DOUG: You're kidding me. What for?
開玩笑吧？去你那兒幹嘛？
I don't know. He just sits in the waiting room and reads Highlights magazine.
我不知道，他就一直呆在等候區，一邊瞎晃一邊讀著Highlights（全球知名兒童刊物）
Fills in the puzzles, whatever he can, and then leaves.
做填字遊戲什麼的，然後就走了
Check it out.
看啊
DOUG: Wow. PHIL: Jesus, what are you gonna do with him?
-哇-天啊，你要對他做什麼？
Actually, I wanted to talk to you guys about that.
事實上，我想跟你說
Linda really wants to stage an intervention for him.
琳達一直想送艾倫去治療
An intervention? Really?
真的嗎？
I think that sounds like a great idea.
聽起來不錯
Yeah, the thing is...
但是…
...she's pretty convinced he won't agree to it unless all of us are there.
她很確信艾倫是不會去的，除非我們幾個去勸
I mean, you know how he is.
你懂艾倫的
I don't know. It seems a little extreme to me.
我不懂，這太難懂了
Oh, God. Look at him now.
天啊，你看看他
Okay, I'm in. When are we doing it?
好吧，我去，什麼時候？
LAUREN: So we talked to Tracy today...
今天我們跟崔西談了談
...and she said that the treatment facility that they found is really nice.
她說他們找的那地方設備挺不錯
It's beautiful. I checked it out online. Great reputation.
環境也好。我上網查了，確實如此
Who gives a fuck? It's in Arizona. We gotta go on like a two-day drive for this shit?
誰他媽管？再好也是在亞利桑那州，開車去個來回也要兩天吧？
Here we go.
走吧
They should just save their money and send him to fat camp.
他們應該省著點，送艾倫去個減肥夏令營什麼的
- Phil. - What?
-菲爾-咋了？
He should lose weight. He'll find a woman. The dude's lonely.
他該減肥了，那哥們太寂寞了，得找個伴兒
If he's so lonely, why don't the you spend more time with him?
那你為什麼不多花點時間陪他呢？
- No, trust me, you don't want that. - No. You definitely don't want that.
-相信我，你也不會這樣做的-你絕對不會
Come on. He's not that bad.
拜託，他沒那麼爛
I mean, what's the worst that's happened? The tattoo?
我是說，還有什麼比紋身那次（醉後大丈夫2）更爛？
Yeah, the tattoo's the worst.
沒錯~這刺青醜爆了
Right?
是吧？
Definitely. Tattoo was the worst. Nightmare.
絕對是，紋身那次絕對是噩夢
Speaking of which, you ever get tested?
說到紋身，你後來去檢查過嗎？
Excuse me?
什麼？
You know, because of the ink.
那些紋身的墨水
That went inside you.
它們進入了你的體內
I'm fine.
我沒事
PHIL: Take care. LAUREN: All right, good luck tomorrow.
-注意安全-好的，明天見
PHIL: Oh, thanks.
謝謝
- I'll pick you up at 11. - Perfect.
-11點我來接你-完美
LAUREN: Thank you so much.
太謝謝你了
Thanks.
謝謝
LINDA: Again, thank you so much for coming. PHIL: Oh, of course.
-再次謝謝你們來-沒關係
This is Nico. Nico is a good friend of Alan's.
這位是尼克，艾倫的一位好朋友
- What's up, bros? PHIL: - Oh, yeah, hey.
-你好嗎？-好
And that's Blanca. Blanca's been with us since Alan was a baby.
這是布蘭卡，她一直照顧艾倫到大
- Hello. - Hello.
-你好-你好
And this is Timothy. Timothy lives across the street.
這位是提摩西，住在對面
He and Alan swim together.
他經常和艾倫一起游泳
- Hey, what's up, little man? - Hey.
-你好嗎？-嘿
- Why don't you guys take a seat? - Yeah.
-坐吧，你們-嗯
[DOUG CLEARS THROAT]
Tracy's on her way back with Alan right now.
崔西載著艾倫在回來的路上
Obviously, he has no idea this is coming, so things might get a little intense.
艾倫不知道接下來要發生什麼，所以一會兒氣氛會有點緊張
But, no matter what happens, remember:
但不管發生什麼，記住
This is all about Alan getting better.
這都是為了艾倫好
Mother, Oreo smoothie, now!
媽，我要奧利奧冰沙
Oh.
哦
- Hey, everyone. - Hey.
-大家好-嘿
Hey, Timothy. Little cold for a swim, isn't it?
嘿，提摩西，今天去游泳有點冷吧？
Oh, wow. Look. You went to the pier today. How was that?
去碼頭玩的開心嗎？
- We had a great time. - Yeah.
-開心-沒錯
I played skee ball for, like, 45 minutes. It was a pretty sick workout.
我玩了會兒滑雪球，真是有夠遜
What's going on?
怎麼了？
Uh, ahem, why don't you have a seat, bud? We just want to talk to you for a sec.
呃，你坐下吧，我們想跟你聊會兒
Okay.
好吧
- Hey, Phil. - Hey. Yeah.
-嘿，菲爾-嘿
- Yeah. - What's going on?
-耶-最近怎樣？
Oh, you got me.
你牛逼
[ALL LAUGHING]
DOUG: So, Alan...
聽著，艾倫
...we're all here to tell you about an awesome place...
我們來這是為了告訴你一個超炫的地方
...called New Horizons.
叫｢新地平線｣
That does sound awesome.
聽起來確實不錯
Alan, this is an intervention.
艾倫，這是一次治療
A what?
什麼？
Mom.
媽
Alan.
艾倫
"I love you so much. We all do."
“我很愛你，我們都愛”
"But we can't keep lying to each other."
但我們不能再欺騙對方了
"Ever since you were a baby, all I want..."
從你小時候開始，我就想…
Oh, my God, is anybody else falling asleep?
天啊，還有人沒睡著嗎？
DOUG: Alan, listen.
聽著，艾倫
- No offense, Mom, but you're boring. BLANCA: - Mr. Alan.
-媽我無意冒犯，但你實在有夠無聊-艾倫先生
Oh, now you?
你新來的吧？
"I pick up after you for 30 years."
“我幫你擦了30年屁股”
"I cleaned your room. I see things no one should ever see."
打掃你的房間，也看到了些不為人知的東西
"But I pray for you."
但是我仍然為你祈禱
- "Mr. Alan, everyone..." PHIL: - Hey.
-艾倫先生，所有人都…-嘿
- Someone should clean that up. - Alan.
-來人把這兒清了-艾倫
Alan. You are not well.
艾倫，你病了
You're off your meds and you're clearly upsetting your whole family.
你沒在接受治療而且你讓你全家人都感到沮喪
- That's baloney. - Alan, if you say yes to this...
-胡扯-艾倫，如果你同意這一切…
...we drive you there today, and I promise you will come back a changed man.
我們今天就載你去那裡，我保證你回來後會大變樣
Who's we? What do you mean, "we"? Who's we?
“我們”是誰？誰是“我們”？
We. All of us. Stu, Phil, me, you.
我們，所有人。菲爾，我，你。
You going, Phil?
你也去嗎，菲爾？
I love you, Alan.
艾倫，我愛你
[CRYING]
[CONTINUES CRYING]
[HARRY NILSSON'S "EVERYBODY'S TALKIN" ' PLAYING ON RADIO]
Hey, Alan, you hungry?
嘿，艾倫，你餓嗎？
You wanna get some Arby's?
要不要去吃點東西？
No, thanks.
不
You know, I meant to tell you earlier, that's a really cool vest you got on.
我早想跟你說了艾倫，你那件背心真屌
Thanks, Phil. It was my dad's.
謝謝你，菲爾，那是我爸的
He died in it.
他穿著它死的
Whoa.
哇
That's intense.
真的好屌
Hey, Alan, just want to say what you're doing is really brave. We're proud of you.
嘿，艾倫，我只想說你是個勇敢的人，我們都為你驕傲
Yeah, you're gonna do great.
沒錯，你可是要做大事的人
Stop the car. I don't want to do this anymore.
停車，我不想做了
- What? - I changed my mind.
-什麼？-我改變主意了
Alan, you can't change your mind. Everybody's counting on you.
艾倫，你不要這樣，大家都看著你呢
I'm fine just the way I am. I want to go home.
我這樣就很好，我想回家
Turn the car around. Now, please! I don't...
調頭，快，現在！我不想…
[CRASHING]
What the fuck was that?
他媽的怎麼了？
- Oh, my God! He's doing it on purpose! - Get out of his way!
-天啊，他們是故意的-快讓路
I am, I am.
我在讓我在讓我在讓
- Hey! Hey, get the fuck off! - You have to exchange information.
-嘿，快滾開！-跟他們說說理
- Why? - Jesus. Phil!
幹什麼？天啊，菲爾！
- Phil! Phil! - Oh, shit!
-菲爾！-幹
[ALL SCREAMING]
- Get away from him! - I'm trying!
-快走！-知道了！
DOUG: - Look out! - Oh, shit!
-小心！-幹！
[SCREAMING]
ALAN: Aw, shit! Oh, shit.
幹幹幹幹幹！
[ALL SCREAMING]
PHIL: Shit!
幹！
Go, go, go!
上！
Lock your doors! Doug, lock your doors!
快鎖門，道格，快鎖門！
ALAN: Shit! What's going on?
幹，到底怎麼了？
[SCREAMING]
Get the fuck... Hang on!
快他媽滾…抓住！
[STU SCREAMS]
STU: Help! PHIL: Let go, fucking asshole!
-救命！-放手，傻子！
[ALAN PANTING]
[STU SCREAMS]
PHIL: Stu! We're okay. STU: We're in an elevator!
-斯圖，我們沒事-我們在電梯裡！
DOUG: Where are you?
你在哪？
[STU CONTINUES SCREAMING]
STU: What the fuck is going on?
他媽的到底怎麼了？
[PHIL COUGHING]
Please, this is a huge mistake.
這一定搞錯了
You got the wrong guys!
你們抓錯人了！
I got the right fucking guys! Get him up. Pick him up. Put him here.
他媽的沒抓錯！帶他過來
- You're Black Doug! That's Black Doug! - Shut the fuck up with that. Shut the fuck up.
-你不是黑道格咩（醉後大丈夫1）！-他媽的閉嘴
Oh, my God. It is.
天啊，還真是
Alan, tell me right now, why is Black Doug kidnapping us?
艾倫，告訴我，為什麼黑道格要綁架我們？
- I said don't call me that shit no more. STU: - Sorry.
-我說了別再叫我黑道格-不好意思
- It ain't Alan's fault. - Thank you, Black Doug.
-這不是艾倫的錯-謝謝你，黑道格
- Motherfucker! PHIL: - Doug!
-王八蛋！-道格！
- Doug! - Okay, okay.
-道格！-好的，好的
- Just Doug, okay? - Yeah.
-叫你野道格行了吧？-好
Why are you doing this?
你幹嘛這麼做？
MARSHALL: Because...
因為…
...I told him to.
是我叫的
I'm Marshall.
我是馬歇爾
And whether you know it or not...
不管你知不知道
...we all have something in common.
我們有一些共同點
And it all started four years ago when this moron...
四年前，這個傻子…
...sold the wrong drugs to this dumb fuck.
賣錯了藥給他
You have no idea the chain of events that were set in motion that night...
那晚隨後發生的一切你根本無法想像
...in the parking lot of a fucking liquor store.
在他媽的一家酒行的停車場裡
What up, nigga?
喲，黑鬼~
Excuse me?
你說什麼？
Chill out, I'm not a cop. Just in town for the night.
放輕鬆，我不是條子，只是來享受夜生活的高富帥
Me and my boys looking to get our freak on.
我和我那幫兄弟們想high一把
You sold Alan roofies.
你把迷奸藥賣給了艾倫
Oh, shit. I must've mixed up the bags.
幹，我一定是搞混那幾個裝藥的袋子了
My fault, Alan.
是我的錯，艾倫
Damn. Marshall gonna be pissed off at me on that one.
他媽的，因為這件事馬歇爾差點幹爆我
(ECHOING) Damn. Marshall gonna be pissed off at me on that one.
[ECHOING] Damn. Marshal! Gonna be pissed off at me on that one.
Marshall?
馬歇爾？
You're Marshall.
你是馬歇爾
You brought us out here because of that?
你因為這個把我們帶到這兒來？
(LAUGHS)
[LAUGHS]
You're not here because of that.
不是
You're here because some Chinaman I never heard of strolls into my town...
你來這兒是因為一個名不見經傳的中國佬到了我的地盤…
...and takes one of my guys off the street.
- Mr. Chow? - Yes.
-周？-沒錯
Yes, Mr. Leslie fucking Chow.
沒錯，就是周那個賤貨
You introduced a virus into my life.
他完完全全擾亂了我的生活
Oh, God, what did he do?
天啊，他幹了什麼？
He fucked me in the ass.
他爆了我的菊花
Oh, he does that from time to time.
哦，他經常這麼幹
Not literally.
不是你想的那個爆菊花
Jesus!
天啊！
A few weeks after your bullshit, I get word...
你們的破事過後幾周，我收到消息…
...this sheik is coming in from Abu Dhabi.
有人從阿布達比（阿拉伯聯合酋長國首都）過來
MARSHALL: He was looking to make some less-than-legal investments.
說是來搞些“投資”
He brought his two wives...
帶著兩個老婆…
...and $42 million in gold bars.
還有價值4千2百萬的金條
It was a lay-up.
休息的時候
MAN: Get down! Get down!
都趴下！趴下！
MARSHALL: We took it all.
我們收下了
Two vans, each with 21 million in gold.
兩輛貨車分裝了這些金條
My guys split up.
我的人分開走
One of them made it back...
一撥回到了
[SIREN WAILING]
...one of them didn't.
另一撥沒有
Is there a problem, officer?
有事咩，警官？
Not anymore, motherfucker.
沒事了，傻屌
[LAUGHING]
Leslie Chow stole $21 million from me...
周偷走了我一半的金條
...on a Tuesday.
那是個星期二
Oh, God.
天啊
I looked everywhere for him.
我到處找他
But he's gone, no one can find him.
但他消失了，誰也找不到他
Until the little cockroach got himself pinched in Bangkok.
直到這個賤貨在曼谷被人抓了（醉後大丈夫2）
Sol pay him a visit.
我去看他
MARSHALL: I offer him a truce.
給他提了個條件
I won't touch a hair on his head.
我不會傷害你
I just want him to tell me where my gold is.
我只想讓他告訴我金條在哪兒
He refuses to talk.
可他不說
Not only does he refuse to talk to me...
不僅不跟我說…
...he has no communication with anyone from the outside...
他還從來沒跟外界聯繫過…
...except you!
除了你
Hey.
他！
It's unfair!
沒理由啊！
Alan, you been talking to Chow?
艾倫，你一直跟周聯絡著？
- They've been writing letters. - Hey, those are private!
-他們一直在寫信-嘿，那是我的隱私！
"Dear Leslie, OMG, the McRib is back! Why was it ever gone?"
“親愛的周，天啊，McRib（麥當勞傳奇漢堡）回來了！”
Exactly!
沒錯！
"Dear Alan, I threw urine on prison guard today."
“親愛的艾倫，我今天尿在了一個獄卒身上
"Blamed it on cellmate. Wish you were here."
嫁禍到了一個獄友身上，真希望你當時也在場”
Yeah, I wish I could've seen that.
沒錯啊，我是希望能親眼目睹
Letter after letter of total nonsense...
一封接著一封毫無意義的信
...except for one common thread:
除了一條共有的線索：
You guys!
你們！
The wolf pack.
狼友
Jesus Christ, Alan.
天啊，艾倫
Five weeks ago, Chow escaped from maximum security detention.
五個星期前，周從安全等級最高的監獄溜了
Oh, fuck.
幹
He stowed aboard a shipping freighter bound for the West Coast.
上了一艘開往西海岸的船
- Where is he? - I don't know.
-他在哪？-我不知道
Alan, if you know where he is, you tell this man right now.
艾倫，如果你知道周在哪，現在就跟這個人說
Phil, I don't know, I swear. I haven't talked to him in months.
菲爾，我發誓我不知道，我幾個月沒跟周聯絡了
We gotta do it the hard way.
看來得來點硬的了
STU: Oh, no! DOUG: What the fuck? Hey!
-不要！-幹什麼？嘿！
MARSHALL: Let's go. DOUG: Hey! No! No! What the fuck?
-走吧-嘿，要幹嘛？
Whoa, what are you doing?
你在做什麼？
Doug is my insurance. He stays with me.
道格現在是我的了
You don't give me Chow, I blow his brains out.
我見不到周，就爆了他的頭
You go to the cops...
你們要是報警…
...I blow his brains out.
我也爆了他的頭
That's insane! We don't even know where the fuck he is!
你瘋了吧，我們根本不知道那個王八蛋在哪
No one does.
沒人知道
But I figure the wolf pack has the best chance of finding him.
但我想身為狼友應該最有可能找到他
You have three days.
給你們三天時間
Get to work.
去吧
Can you take Stu instead?
把道格換成斯圖好咩？
Fuck you, Alan.
幹你大爺，艾倫
Shit.
幹
Shit!
幹！
PHIL: Alan. ALAN: Yeah, Phil?
-艾倫-幹嘛？
PHIL: I need you to roll over here and chew off these hand-ties.
我要你滾過來咬斷這些繩子
ALAN: Okay.
好
- Oh. ALAN: - Damn it!
-哦-幹！
Ow. Oh, fuck!
哦，哦，幹！
ALAN: Got a little too much steam. PHIL: Get off me.
-我被曬傷了-快滾開
ALAN: All right, let me just shimmy down.
好，我走
- Would you just hold still? Hold still! PHIL: - Ow.
-你能別動嗎？-噢
STU: Help!
救命！
Help!
PHIL: Holy shit.
幹
What are we gonna do, Stu?
斯圖，接下來幹嘛？
STU: - We're gonna go to the police. - Oh, no, we're fucking not.
-我們要去報警-不，千萬別
Did you hear that guy?
你沒聽到那哥們說的？
He will kill Doug, period.
報警他就爆了道格的頭
Chow is a cancer.
周就是個毒瘤子
He's been a cancer since the first day we met him.
第一天遇見他我就這麼覺得
We're gonna hand him over to Marshall and then it's done.
把周交給馬歇爾，萬事大吉
- Hey, Phil. - Alan, not now.
-嘿，菲爾-艾倫，現在沒空
But I need you, Stu. I can't do this alone.
你得幫我，我一個人沒法做
Do what alone? We have no idea where he even is.
做什麼？我們根本不知道周在哪
- Phil. - What, Alan?
-菲爾-艾倫，你要幹嘛？
I was gonna say I got this strange e-mail the other day.
我說我前幾天收到了這封奇怪的e-mail
I wasn't sure what it meant, but now I think it might be from Chow.
我不知道什麼意思，但我認為可能是周發的
"Fatty, it feels good to be out."
“肥仔，自由的感覺真好”
"I'm close by. Tell no one. I'll be in touch."
我離你不遠了，別跟別人說，我會聯繫你的
"Chow."
周（音同義大利語“再見”）
This says "Chow." How did you not know this was from Chow?
這上面寫的是周，你又怎麼不知道是周發的？
At the time, I thought it was "Chow" like "goodbye."
那時候我以為是“Ciao”（義大利語），再見的意思
You know, like, "Chow, arrivederci."
你懂的啊，就好像，“再見，拜拜~”（均為義大利語）
- You know, Sbarro, Papa John's. - I'm writing him back.
-Sbarro，Papa John's啊（均為美國披薩品牌）-我這就給他回信
Whoa, wait, wait. Just hold on.
哇，等等，等一等
Gonna tell him you're happy he's out and you'd love to see him.
我跟他將你很高興他能越獄，想見他
Ooh, I would love to see him.
那就太好了
Do you even know what's going on?
你們知不知道你們在幹嘛？
Yes, I do. Phil's doing all the work, I'm his assistant...
知道啊，菲爾在做對事，而我是他的助手
- ...you're standing there looking like an idiot. - I'm gonna arrange a meeting...
而你站在那裡看著像個傻子，我得安排個會面
- ...and we're gonna take him out. - "Take him out"?
然後我們把周約出來-約出來？
Who says that? How do we take someone out?
誰說約的？我們要怎麼約？
We'll use drugs.
我們得用點藥
Prescription drugs.
處方藥~
You know, the kind a dentist has access to.
你懂的，牙醫都能開的那種
Good luck finding a dentist who will write fake prescriptions.
真幸運我們有一個會開假處方的牙醫
Oh, I know one. His name is Stuart Price.
哦我認識他，他叫斯圖
Now let's go find a fucking pharmacy.
走吧，找個藥店去
Whoo! You just got schooled, son.
你上道了，小子
Are you coming or not?
你來不來？
I don't like this plan.
我不怎麼想來
Okay, then. Ciao.
好吧，那麼再見~
[ALAN LAUGHS]
I got a pretty dope sense of humor, bro!
我真他媽的有幽默感
[ALAN CONTINUES LAUGHING]
MAN: This amount with syringes is just weird. Go check it out.
要這麼多注射器幹嘛？去問問看
Everything okay?
沒事吧？
Well, it's just a strange request.
你要的東西真夠奇怪
This drug in this amount and a pack of syringes.
這麼多的藥還有一包注射器
- It's just a little weird. - Yeah.
-有一點奇怪啊-耶
It's just kind of an emergency, so...
出了點狀況，所以…
See, that right there, and you're acting all fidgety, plus you look like shit...
看看你，坐立不安，加上一副狼狽的模樣
...in our business, these are all red flags.
在我們這行看來，這些都是危險信號
I need to call the doctor, make sure everything's okay.
我得找下醫生，確保一切正常
Aha. You're in luck, because I actually am the prescribing doctor.
啊哈，要找醫生的話你可真就找對人了，在下正式醫生
Oh, boy. Another red flag.
幹，又一個危險信號
It says here you're a dentist.
這上面說你是個牙醫啊
Yeah. Doctor of Dental Science.
牙醫就不是醫生啊
This is fucked up.
真他媽的亂
Hey, Dad?
爸？
I think we got a live one.
有個活著的癮君子
How'd we do?
怎樣？
We did good. I got Demerol, a pack of syringes...
挺好的，拿到了杜米諾和一袋注射器
(Demerol, Pethidine化學合成的強效嗎啡類麻醉止痛藥)
...and almost lost my dental license.
還差點丟了我的牙醫執照
- What about Chow? Anything? - No.
-周有什麼消息嗎？-沒
Oh, look at this. He e-mailed me like 20 minutes ago.
看啊，周20分鐘前給我電郵了
Alan, we've been sit...
艾倫，我們坐這兒都…
Give me the phone, please.
把電話給我
- What does it say? - Oh, wow.
-周說了啥？-哇
He wants to meet Alan tonight at 8. It says come alone.
他今晚八點想見艾倫，上面說讓艾倫自己去
- Come alone where? - A bus stop.
-自己去哪？-巴士站
In Tijuana.
在提華納（墨西哥西北部城市）
Tijuana's the bomb.
提華納完了
Oh, fuck.
幹
No, that's perfect. No, it's like a three-hour drive from here.
這下好了，從這兒到提華納要三小時車程
Yeah, Stu, try reading a map.
斯圖，麻煩多看看地圖
Yeah, Alan, try reading anything ever.
是啊艾倫，下次有消息了麻煩吱一聲
Yeah, Stu, try not having such big horse teeth.
好吧斯圖，麻煩別這麼囉嗦
PHIL: All right, we need a plan.
我們需要個計畫
They're meeting on a bus bench in a public place...
周和艾倫要在公車站的長椅上見面
...so Alan needs to convince Chow to go someplace more private.
所以艾倫要讓周確信那裡很安全
Someplace where we can sneak up on him and drug him.
而那地方我們又能觀察他，給他下藥
Like where?
哪裡呢？
I don't know, like an alley.
我不知道啊，小巷裡吧
What about a movie theater?
電影院怎麼樣？
Fuck, that's actually a great idea.
我幹，好主意啊
The lights go down...
光線變暗…
...we take the seats behind him, we jab him and it's fucking done.
我坐在周後面，給他下藥，事兒就這麼完了
I'll jab him if you want. I've drugged people before.
下藥這事兒我在行
Yeah, us.
是我們
No offense, but we're not letting you handle any drugs. You'll kill someone.
無意冒犯，可我們是不會讓你自己一個人去的
Oh, please, I'm an expert.
別鬧了，我是專家
Remember the marshmallows in Thailand?
記不記得泰國那次的棉花糖（醉後大丈夫2）？
Yeah?
啊？
I made it so you could eat at least three before hitting a fatal dose.
那次我的量掐的剛好，你們沒人至少吃了三個也還沒死
Wait.
等等
So you're saying I would've died if I had had four?
你的意思是如果我吃了四個就死了？
Nobody eats four marshmallows, Stu.
沒人會一次吃四個棉花糖的，斯圖
That insane theory is the only reason I'm still alive?
我能活著還得謝謝你這理論咯？
Yes! And you're welcome, by the way.
沒錯，不用謝
STU: Don't say "you're welcome" for almost killing me.
你差點殺了我，別說“不用謝”了
- Fine. - Thank you.
-好吧-謝謝
- You're welcome. - Goddamn it!
-不用謝-幹！
[THE COASTERS' "DOWN IN MEXICO" PLAYING ON RADIO]
PHIL: Oh, God.
天啊
You know, you were right.
你是對的
- About what? - That place in Arizona. It's not gonna help him.
-哪對了？-送艾倫去治療根本沒用
There is no facility that can fix this guy.
這哥們沒得救了
We're gonna spend the rest of our lives dealing with him...
我們下輩子還得陪他
...because we're all he has now.
“因為我們是他現在的一切”
You realize that? We're it.
你知道了嗎？
Oh, shit, check it out.
幹，看
Is that Chow?
是周嗎？
Hey, fat stuff.
嘿，肥仔
- Leslie. - Uh-uh-uh.
-周-啊啊啊
- Act cool. Eyes forward. - Yeah, okay.
-自然點，往前看-好
- Anyone follow you? - No, I don't think so.
-有人跟著你咩？-沒有
Good, good.
好的，好的
Gotta keep low profile right now. Chow wanted man.
哥現在可是頭號人物，得低調點
Can't trust anyone.
誰也信不得
Quick, give me some sugar. Come on, come on, come on.
給哥來點糖吃，快
PHIL: What the fuck?
搞什麼？
Did he just kiss him?
艾倫親周了？
Listen, I'm in a bit of a pickle, Alan.
聽著，艾倫，哥現在有點麻煩
- I need a friend. - Well, I'm your friend, Leslie.
-我需要個朋友-我不是嗎？
Exactly. That's why I called you down here.
這正是我找你來的原因
You're the only person I can trust in this shit-hole of a life.
你是哥這操蛋的一生中唯一可以相信的人
That's not true. Stu and Phil are your friends.
不是吧，斯圖和菲爾咩？
Oh, really?
他們？
That's interesting.
真有趣
Where are they?
他們在哪？
- Around. - Around where?
-附近-附近是哪裡？
I don't know.
我不知道
- Motherfucker! I told you to come alone! - Leslie.
幹！我不是讓你自己來嗎？
Shit.
幹
- What happened? STU: - Is he leaving?
-怎麼了？-周要走了？
ALAN: We'll talk more! I'll give you another kiss!
回頭聊！我還會吻你的！
STU: He's coming this way.
周過來了
Get down. Get down.
趴下，快趴下
PHIL: - Fuck. - Leslie!
-幹-周！
Oh, fuck.
媽的
- Get out of the car, you mutts! - Leslie, no!
-出來，你們這幫混蛋！-不要，周
- Get off me, fat clown! - Chow! Chow, calm down!
-放開我，死肥仔！-冷靜地，周！
- Who sent you? - No one! No.
-誰讓你們來的？-沒人
- We just wanted to see you! - Liar! No one wants to see Chow!
-我們只是想見你！-騙人，沒人想見我！
No, we... We miss you.
我們…我們想你啊
- What? - We miss you, Chow!
-啥？-周，我們想你
- That's it. - Yeah.
-就這麼簡單-耶
We miss you.
我們想你
You miss me?
你們想我？
So much.
非常想
You miss Chow.
你們想我
Yeah, buddy.
對啊
We love you, Chow.
我們愛你啊，老周
(SINGING) I hurt myself today
To see if I still feel
I focus on the pain
The only thing that's real
What have I become
What the fuck am I watching?
我在看什麼鬼東西？
My sweetest friend
Everyone I know
Goes away in the end
- Is that gonna be enough? STU: - Oh, yeah.
-要完了嗎？-是吧
This will take about a minute to kick in. We'll tell the waitress he's drunk.
這東西得一會才能溶好，到時我們就跟服務員說他喝醉了
By the time we get to the car, he'll be out cold.
他會一直暈著，被我們拖上車
My empire of dirt
I will let you down
I will make you hurt
[CROWD APPLAUDS]
Alan, sit down.
坐下，艾倫
That was really nice, Chow.
唱的真不錯啊，周
Thanks, Phil.
謝謝
The key is to sing from your heart.
關鍵是要唱出心裡的歌
So Mexico, huh? What are you doing down here?
很墨西哥哈？你在這裡幹嘛？
You know, fucking, doing blow. Same old, same old.
搞一搞，吹一吹咯，老樣子
Ooh, I got into cockfighting.
哦，我還鬥雞
- Oh, cockfighting. That sounds wonderful. CHOW: - Yes.
-哦，聽起來很屌-沒錯
Basically, been killing it down here.
鬥遍墨西哥無敵手
That is just terrific. Right?
屌啊
I mean, that's terrific. I think that calls for a toast.
我覺得，就沖你的鬥雞，咱得幹一杯
I like that.
沒錯
- To killing it. - Killing it.
-鬥爆別的雞-鬥爆它們
Yeah, to killing it.
沒錯，鬥爆它們
Mm.
嗯
You okay, Chow?
你還好咩？
I don't know. You tell me.
你說說看我好不好吧
(CHUCKLES)
[CHUCKLES]
So how many rooster birds do you have, Chow?
你有幾隻雞？周
- Aah! - Huh?
-啊！-哈？
- Shh. Act cool or I open his vein. - Oh, my God.
-安靜點，不然我就割斷他的脖子-天啊
Why you wanna drug poor Chow?
你們為什麼要給可憐的老周下藥？
No, no. It's not what you think. There's this guy Marshall.
不是你想的那樣子，周，都是那個馬歇爾叫的
Marshall? How you know that fat fuck?
馬歇爾？你們怎麼會認識那個傻子？
He says you took his gold. He's got Doug. He'll kill him unless we bring you back.
他說你拿了他的金條，把道格抓走了，我們不把你帶去他就把道格殺了
It's true! I swear to God, it's true!
沒錯，我發誓，是真的
Chow. Chow, that's the truth.
這是事實，周
Goddamn it!
幹！
That motherfucker.
那個混蛋
Stu, you okay?
斯圖，你還好嗎？
- You all right? - No.
-你還好嗎？-不好
PHIL: We're sorry, Chow.
對不起，周
We're sorry.
對不起
- We didn't know what else to do. - Next time, don't lie to Chow.
-我們不知道怎麼做-下次別騙周
You're right. You are so right, and we made a huge mistake.
你是對的，我們錯了
So, what do we do now?
那麼，我們現在該怎麼辦？
CHOW: That depends.
看情況
Can I trust you?
我能信你們嗎？
What is this place, Chow?
這是哪兒？
CHOW: My house.
我的房子
Chow used to be on top of the world.
哥曾經是世界之王
Had three beautiful homes in three different countries.
有三幢漂亮的房子在三個不同的國家
But this one, my Mexican villa...
但墨西哥的這棟別墅
...this was my favorite.
是我的最愛
And everything got fucked.
結果事情搞砸了
Chow go to prison, all my property seized.
哥進去了，哥的財產都沒了
My homes...
我的房子…
...sold at auction to highest bidders.
被拿來拍賣
But I know something no one else knows.
但我知道些猛料
This house is where I stashed the gold.
這幢房子是我拿來藏金條用的
- Marshall's gold? - Yep.
-馬歇爾的金條？-沒錯
Hid it inside the basement wall.
藏在地下室的牆裡
No one knows it's there.
沒人知道在那裡
We're gonna go get it.
我們去把金條搞到手
Wait. You mean break in?
等等，你是說闖進去？
Look, Marshall wants his gold.
聽著，馬歇爾想要他的金條
And he's gonna hunt me down until he gets it.
拿到之前他會一直追殺我的
If we show up without it, he'll kill me.
如果我們去找他不帶著金條，他會殺了我的
We're not breaking in anywhere.
我們是不會闖進任何地方的
Not anywhere, Stu. My house.
這不是別的地方，是我的房子
It's piece of cake.
簡直小菜一碟
I know every square inch of this place.
我對這裡瞭若指掌
The best part, the guy we're stealing it from doesn't even know it's there.
最妙的是，我們要闖的這家主人根本不知道那裡有金條
So he'll never know it's gone.
所以他也不會知道金條沒了
You guys know what's going on, right?
我們明白吧？哈？
What do you mean?
你什麼意思？
Well, and please correct me if I'm wrong, we're not breaking into this house.
我要說錯了麻煩指正我，我們不是闖進這房子
This house is too small.
這房子太小了
We're breaking into another house. This is just a model, right?
我們是要闖進另外一幢房子，這只是個模型，對嗎？
What? Alan, no!
什麼？艾倫，不要！
My chickens!
我的雞！
[PHIL GRUNTING AND STU SCREAMING]
Oh, shit!
幹！
PHIL: Chow, what the fuck?
周，搞什麼？
CHOW: Watch out for the claws! They're trained to kill!
小心它們的爪，很危險
His beak is so sharp!
它的喙好尖
Ow! Ow!
喔！喔！
(GUNSHOT)
[GUNSHOT]
- Oh, fuck! - Stay still, I'm trying to help.
-幹！-別動，我是來幫忙的
- Don't! STU: - Get it off!
不要！把它拿走！
- Fucking bull's-eye! - Are you out of your mind?
-哥要正中靶心-你瘋啦？
Shoot it! Shoot it! Shoot it!
射！射！射！
PHIL: Stu, the window!
斯圖，窗！
- Get it out! - Okay, okay!
-扔出去-好的！
Get it out!
扔出去！
CHOW: Shh, shh, shh.
噓
Don't struggle. Let go.
別掙扎了
You won a lot of fights, Wallace.
你為我贏過很多比賽，華萊士
Not this time.
但這次你輸了
(GRUNTING)
[GRUNTING]
- What the fuck is wrong with those chickens? - They're angry.
-這些雞到底怎麼了？-它們很憤怒
All I feed them is cocaine.
我拿可卡因來喂它們
And chicken.
還有雞肉
[CHOW LAUGHS]
PHIL: That's some house, Chow.
這房子真屌
CHOW: It was my Shangri-La. Now it's gone.
這可是我的仙境，現在不是了
Could you not spit inside my minivan, please? Jesus.
能別在我的車裡吐口水咩？
Who lives there now?
現在誰住那兒？
CHOW: Some dot-com millionaire. He's never here.
搞網路公司的屌絲，他從不住在這裡
This is a vacation home.
這裡只是拿來度假的
The help doesn't show up on Sundays.
保姆週六不來
No one there but the guard dogs. Stu?
只有幾隻看門狗哈，斯圖？
We'll toss these burgers over the gate, wait for the Demerol to kick in.
我們把混著杜米諾的漢堡扔過們去給狗吃
Make sure you put in enough to kill them.
一定得把它們殺了
We're not gonna kill the dogs, Chow.
我們才不要殺狗，周
This will knock them out for hours.
這只會讓它們昏迷幾個小時
Oh, I'm sorry. I didn't know you worked for PETA.
不好意思，我不知道你在PETA（善待動物組織善待動物組織）工作
- What a pussy. - Ha-ha-ha.
-真是個娘炮-哈哈哈
[BARKING]
Alan, take that.
拿著，艾倫
Aah!
啊！
[GRUNTING]
- Where are you going? - You'll see.
-你去哪裡？-你會知道的
Pardon me, little loser.
原諒我，寶貝
Excuse me, fucking asshole.
不好意思
Follow me.
跟著我
CHOW: Okay, here's the deal: two security panels inside.
咱把流程再走一遍，屋裡有兩處控制台
If you cut only one wire, it triggers alarm.
你掐了一個，另一個就響了
Place will be crawling with cops.
條子就來了
But if you cut wire on both panels at same time, alarm disabled.
但如果你兩個一起掐，就不會響
Yeah, but how are we gonna get inside without tripping the alarm?
是啊，但我們怎麼才能不觸動警報然後進去？
Check this out.
好好瞧著
[CHOW CHUCKLES]
- Any more stupid questions? PHIL: - Whoa.
-還有問題咩？-哇
Now, who's coming with me?
誰要跟著我？
I'll do it.
我來吧
You wanna tell him?
你想告訴他世界的真實嗎？
Oh, um...
嗯……
Alan, you're just too fat.
艾倫，你太胖了
Roger that.
收到
Ow. Ahh.
噢，啊
CHOW: You kicked me, you motherfucker.
你踢我，你這個混蛋
No, no, no. Don't get up. Will trip motion detectors.
不不不，別起來，會觸發動作偵測器
Stay low like dog.
像條狗樣走
Okay. Good idea.
好吧，好主意
- Which way? - In there. The kitchen.
-哪邊？-那兒，廚房
Aah! What the fuck is that?
搞什麼？
Ha, ha. I'm saying hello. We're dogs, remember?
哈哈，我在跟你問好啊，我們是狗，忘了啊？
[CHOW LAUGHS]
Hey, Stu?
嘿，斯圖？
Check it out.
看看這個
Oh, my God! So gross!
天啊，真噁心
[RETCHES]
[LAUGHING]
God! Chow, cut it out!
不要這樣，周
Okay, I'm here.
好了，我到位了
Now what?
現在呢？
Pull the cover off so you can see the wires.
把蓋子拆了，你就能看到線
Okay.
好
Okay. Done!
好了
CHOW: Okay, on three, cut the gray wire.
數到三，剪斷灰線
One, two...
一，二…
STU: Wait. Wait, wait, wait!
等下，等下！
I don't have a gray wire. I have red, green and yellow.
我這兒沒灰線，只有紅、綠和黃線
That's weird. I have light gray, medium gray, dark gray.
奇怪了，我這兒有淡灰、中灰和深灰色的線
You do?
真的？
Motherfucker.
幹林蛤仔!
My bad. I'm colorblind.
怪我了，我是色盲
You're what?
你是啥？
CHOW: Fuck it, just cut the middle one.
不管了，把中間那根剪了
No, my middle one could be different. The wires are all twisted.
不，我中間那根有可能跟你的不同，線都繞一起了
CHOW: - On three. One, two... - Chow, stop!
-數到三。一，二…-周，住手！
God.
天啊
Hold on, I'm coming to you.
別動，我去找你
What the fuck's taking them so long?
他們搞什麼鬼這麼久？
Where'd you get that shirt, the Diesel store?
你這襯衫哪兒買的？Diesel？
Phil.
菲爾
What?
幹嘛？
It's a cute top. Where did you get that shirt?
真好看，你這襯衫哪兒買的？
CHOW: What's the problem?
什麼問題？
Just point to the wire you want me to cut.
把你想剪的線指給我看
- This gray one right here. - Great.
-這根灰的-好的
For your information, that's green.
照你說的，這是根綠線
Ooh, tsk, tsk, tsk.
嘖嘖嘖
Which one's red?
哪根是紅的？
The one in your left hand.
你左手那根
- Wait, which hand is that? I'm also dyslexic. - What the fuck?
-等等，左手是哪只？我讀寫困難-搞什麼？
- Where'd you get it? - I don't know. I'll find out, I'll get you one.
-你去哪裡買的？-我不知道，我找到了會給你買一件的
There's a cool Diesel store in the mall that I like to go to. Right next to the food court.
我常去的那家商場就有家Diesel
I don't know if it's Diesel.
我不知道這件衣服是不是Diesel的
Looks like a Diesel.
看起來像
What's the matter with you?
你到底有什麼病？
Okay, you're still holding the one I left you with, right?
好的，你還拿著我給你的那根線吧？
CHOW: Pretty much. Heh, heh.
那必須的
STU: Oh, fuck.
媽的
All right. On three!
好的，數到三
One...
一
...two...
二
...three.
三
(SIGHS)
[SIGHS]
CHOW: Holy shit, it worked.
媽呀，奏效了
All good?
沒事了？
- Easy peasy. PHIL: - All right.
小菜一碟
You have no idea.
你根本想不到多簡單
Come on.
來吧
Whoops.
喔
- Jesus, be careful, Chow. - Ha, ha.
小心點，周
Fuck this guy.
幹爆這傻屌
Living in my house. Living my life.
住我的房子，過我的生活
Can we just stick to the plan?
能照著計畫走咩？
Fine.
好
Ha, ha. Ruined.
哈哈，廢了
He is completely out of control.
這哥們瘋了
Let's just get this done.
咱把大事先辦了吧
This way. Come on, come on.
這邊走，過來， 過來
It's buried behind this wall.
就埋在這堵牆後
- Alan. - Here you go, boss.
-艾倫-給你，老大
Aah!
啊！
Fuck!
幹！
- You okay? CHOW: - Yeah, I'm okay.
-你好嗎？-很好
Just warming up.
熱個身而已
It's so heavy. Do we have a lighter one?
真重，有輕點的咩？
- Why don't you just let me do it, Chow? - Okay. Either way, you or me. Same thing.
-讓我來吧，周-好吧， 你來我來都一樣
You might wanna take your shirt off. Makes it easier.
把衣服脫了吧，好幹活
- What? - I've heard that too.
-啥？-我聽到了
[PANTING]
See that? Chow come back for you.
看到了嗎？老周回來找你們了
PHIL: That's the last of it.
這是最後的了
You sure?
確定？
- Yeah. - You triple sure?
-嗯-真的確定？
- Yes! - Good! Heh-heh-heh.
-嗯！-好的，哈哈哈
Chow?
周？
Chow!
周！
Chow, open this fucking door right now!
周，快點他媽的開門！
PHIL: Chow!
周！
[ALARM BLARING]
OFFICER: Stuart Price.
史都華·普萊斯
No felonies. One arrest:
沒犯過重罪，被抓過一次
Las Vegas, Nevada.
內華達州，拉斯維加斯
Phil Wenneck.
菲爾·溫內克
No felonies. One arrest:
沒犯過重罪，被抓過一次
Also Las Vegas, Nevada.
還是在內華達州，拉斯維加斯
Alan Garner.
艾倫·加納
Is this record accurate?
這上面記的沒錯吧？
Uh-huh.
嗯哼
I did that. Mm-hm.
都是我幹的，嗯
Yeah.
耶
Masturbating on a city bus. Yep, that was me.
-公車上打手槍-沒錯是我
Look, we've been here for 5 hours.
聽著，我們在這兒5小時了
We already told your guys everything.
該說的都說了
No.
沒有
You told them a story about a little Chinese man.
你只說了個中國佬的故事
Leslie Chow. He's an international criminal. Look it up.
周，他是個國際罪犯，關起來
A little Chinese man that no one in town has seen or heard of.
一個沒人聽說過的中國佬
The hotel where you say he's staying? No one there.
你們說的那家賓館也找不到他
Probably because he left town.
搞不好他已經出城了
That's one theory.
這是一種可能
Another theory is that you're lying.
另外一種是你在撒謊
[ALAN LAUGHING]
"Lewd behavior, Cracker Barrel, Christmas Eve."
“行為淫蕩，舉止下流，在聖誕前夕”
[SPEAKING IN SPANISH]
Excuse me.
不好意思
We're fucking dead.
我們完了
Why would Mr. Chow do this?
周為什麼這麼做？
Because he's a greedy piece of shit who used us.
因為他是個利用我們的貪婪的小人
- Yeah, but he's our friend. - Oh.
-沒錯，可他也是我們的朋友-哦
Grow up, Alan.
別傻了，艾倫
You're free to leave.
你們可以走了
All the charges have been dropped.
所有的指控都被撤銷了
By who?
誰撤的？
OFFICER: It's your lucky day.
你們走運了
There's a car waiting for you out front.
門外有輛車在等你們
Come on, let's go.
來吧，我們走
PHIL: Oh, Jesus.
哦，天啊
What?
什麼？
I'm sorry.
對不起
What is this?
這是什麼意思？
Get in the car.
上車吧
PHIL: Excuse me, sir?
不好意思，先生？
Where we headed?
我們要去哪兒？
(DOORS LOCK)
[DOORS LOCK]
Welcome back.
歡迎回來
- What the fuck? - Let's go, guys.
-搞什麼-走吧
Out to the back.
到後面去
- Doug? - Guys. Careful.
-道格？-小心，夥計們
Get your ass back over here.
你給我過來
Leslie Chow never lived here.
周那死鬼不住在這裡
You didn't break into his old house.
你們闖的根本不是他的舊房子
You broke into my house.
是我的房子
I don't understand.
我不明白
You didn't get back the gold he stole from me.
你們沒拿回周偷走的金條
You got the other half that he didn't.
反倒讓他把另一半也偷走了
Oh. my God!
天啊
What, you mean the half he never had?
你是說周沒拿到的那一半？
He's a world-class rat, and you three were his accomplices.
周是個世界級的小偷，你們只是他的工具
- No! - We had no idea.
-不！-我們根本不知道
We were trying to help you. We thought you'd be happy!
我們是想幫你來著
Thank you so much.
太感謝了
Thank you for ripping me off.
太感謝你們把我給洗劫一空了
Thank you for desecrating my home!
太感謝你們掃蕩了我的家！
And thank you for killing my fucking dogs!
還有要感謝你們殺了我的狗！
We didn't kill your dogs. They're just tranquilized.
我們沒殺，它們只是暈過去了
Oh, right.
沒錯
You don't know.
你懂個屁
- Chow snapped their necks on his way out. - What?
-周走時扭斷了它們的脖子-啥？
And somebody's gotta pay.
有人要為此付出代價
- He's right. - No, no, no! Aah!
-他說的沒錯-不要，不要！啊！
[ALL SCREAMING]
[ALAN WAILING]
My head of security.
我的保安頭子
Couldn't stop three fuckups and a Chinaman with a pair of wire cutters.
連三個傻子和一個拿著剪線鉗的中國佬都比不上
Unreal.
太扯了吧
Aw. Man.
噢，天
That's okay. I know it's scary.
沒關係，我知道這很嚇人
Hector. Run upstairs and grab a pair of sweatpants for Alan here.
海格特，上樓給艾倫拿條褲子
I'm a 44 slim.
我穿44碼的
Can you bring me a few options?
等多拿幾條讓我選咩？
You found Chow once. Find him again.
你們找到過周，再找一次
And my gold.
還有我的金條
Wait.
等著
We don't even have a car. Chow stole my minivan.
我們連車都沒，周偷走了我的車
Take the limo. Hector has the keys.
那輛轎車歸你們了，找海格特拿鑰匙
And get going.
然後滾蛋
I'm killing Dougs today.
我今天把道格殺了
- I never saw anyone get killed before. - Right?
-我從沒見過殺人-是嗎？
My God, that was so intense.
天啊，當時人家好怕
I mean, he just fell and then he's dead.
那哥們就這麼死了
I feel sick.
真噁心
Me too.
我也覺得
Well, maybe we should get some food, guys.
或許我們該找點吃的
What are we gonna do? We have no idea where Chow is.
我們該怎麼做？我們根本不知道周在哪裡？
I don't know.
我也不知道
He took your minivan. We could report it stolen...
他偷了你的車，我們可以報失…
...and then they could track him down?
然後員警會追蹤到他？
It's worth a shot.
值得一試
Oh, fuck!
幹！
I left my phone in the minivan.
我的手機落在車裡了
Well, if you lost your phone, Phil, I have that Find My Phone app.
如果你丟了你的手機，我這有個軟體可以找回來
We have bigger problems than that, Alan.
這不是當下要解決的問題，艾倫
No, wait, wait, wait. If your phone's in the minivan...
等等，等等，如果你的手機在車裡…
...and Chow has the minivan, then your phone's with Chow!
而周偷了你的車，那麼你的手機就和周在一起！
You heard him. We have bigger problems than that, Stu.
你聽到他說的了，我們的問題不是這個，斯圖
Alan, give me your phone. Quick.
艾倫，把你的手機給我，快點
- That's brilliant. - Yes.
-屌-沒錯
- Wait, what's your password? - "Hey Phil."
-你的密碼是？-“Hey Phil.”
- Yeah? - No, that's it.
-耶？-沒錯，就是它
- What? - That's my password.
-什麼？-我手機的密碼
"Hey Phil."
嘿，菲爾
It is it.
就是它
Phil gets it.
菲爾知道了
Nothing worse than losing your phone.
沒什麼比丟了手機更不好的了
You just saw a man get murdered. Your brother-in-law is kidnapped.
你剛剛看到個人被殺了，你的姐夫被綁了
You sure there's nothing worse?
你確定這些都比丟手機好？
You don't get it, Stu.
你不懂
You just don't get it, do you?
你就是不懂，斯圖
I have over 60 apps on that phone.
我的手機上有超過60個軟體
What if I lost my phone?
丟了怎麼辦？
Do you have any idea how much time and man-hours it would take...
你知不知道我得花多久…
...to re-download those apps?
才能重新手動下載這些軟體？
You are right. I had not thought of that. Thank you.
你說的對，我是沒想過，謝謝你
Oh, God, it's not always about you, Stu!
天啊，怎麼腦殘的老是你，斯圖！
It's locating.
找到了
- Oh, God, of course. - What?
-真的找到了-什麼？
Where is he?
周在哪？
He's in fucking Vegas.
那混蛋在拉斯維加斯
- Shotgun. - Oh.
-拉斯維加斯完了-喔
Oh, no.
哦不
Hey, Stu?
嘿，斯圖
I don't enjoy talking to you that way.
我不是很喜歡和你這樣交談
I don't know why you insist on making me blow my top.
我不知道為什麼你老是想激怒我
We've been on a lot of adventures together...
我們一起經歷過這麼多次冒險…
...but it seems like you haven't learned anything.
但你看起來還是什麼都沒學到
Anything!
什麼都沒有！
You think on it.
你好好想想
I'll be in the limo.
我在車裡等你
He's okay.
他沒事
Someone needs to burn this place to the ground.
得有人把這炸了
I told myself I would never come back.
我告誡自己再也不要來了
Well, don't worry.
別擔心
It all ends tonight.
今晚過後一切就結束了
It says 200 yards up on the right.
這上面說就在我們右邊200碼
And there it is.
就是那裡
Amazing.
WOW
Looks like he ditched it.
看來周不要這車了
- It's open. - No shit.
-門沒鎖-幹
Well, look around.
轉轉看看
Let's see if he left anything in here.
周有沒有落東西在車裡
- I found the Demerol. - Good. Keep it, we're gonna need it.
-我找到了杜米諾-好的，留著，我們要用
I got my phone. No fucking keys, though.
我找到手機了，但他媽的鑰匙不見了
- Alan, anything? - No, not even the gold.
-艾倫，你找到了什麼？-沒找到金條
- Why the fuck would Chow come down here? - I know, right?
-周到底他媽的來這裡幹嘛？-我知道的
Why here?
為什麼？
ANNOUNCER (ON TV): You can't match the pure strength and power...
...of John Cena!
- Cena puts Punk down! CASSIE: - Oh! Ha, ha.
Nice!
棒！
Excuse me. Have you happened to see the driver...
不好意思，你有沒有看到過…
...of that minivan that's out front? Short Asian guy?
門口那輛車的司機？一個矮矮的中國佬
Yeah, they're all short.
中國佬都很矮好咩？
Ha, ha. That's so true.
哈哈，沒錯
Right, but he may have been trying to pawn some gold.
沒錯，不過他是否來典當一些金條
That would be my business, wouldn't it?
這就和我有關了是嗎？
ALAN: I like your T-shirt.
我喜歡你的上衣
I saw that show at the Forum.
我看過那場秀
He played "Captain Jack."
他唱了”Captain Jack“
Yeah, I heard that was legendary.
是啊，很棒的一首歌
Woman...
美女…
...you have no idea.
妳絕對無法想像
Try me.
試看看
Cassie, I'm hungry. I thought you ordered Chinese.
凱西，我餓了，你訂的中國菜呢
Mom, I'm with a customer!
媽我這兒有客人！
- You'll eat when I say it's time to eat! - But the doctor...
-我說什麼時候吃就什麼時候吃！-可醫生…
If you don't reverse that right now, there's gonna be hell to pay.
如果你不把那台電動輪椅折返，會有妳好受的
[LAUGHS]
[ALAN CONTINUES LAUGHING]
She's rude.
她真沒禮貌
Thank you.
謝謝
Yeah, you hear that, Ma? Nobody likes you!
聽到了嗎？沒人喜歡你，老傢伙
Yeah, keep your mouth shut!
沒錯，閉上你的臭嘴
Whoa.
哇
You're smart.
你真聰明
A Chinese guy came in here earlier.
一個中國佬早些時候來過
It was pretty weird.
很奇怪
He pawned a gold brick.
他拿來一個金條
The thing's worth 400 grand, he took 18,000.
值40萬的金條他只要了1萬8
- Did he say where he was going? - I'm sorry, was I talking to you?
-他說他要去哪了嗎？-我有在跟你說話咩？
He said he wanted three things:
他說他要三樣東西
He wanted some girls, some guys and some bath salts.
妹子，漢子，還有浴鹽
I gave him a card for an escort service and he took off.
我給了他一張三陪服務的卡然後他走了
Pretty high-end, so good luck getting anything out of them.
也給你們一張吧，這服務絕對屌爆
Thank you.
謝謝你
[RETCHES]
We gotta go. We should go.
我們得走了
- Yeah. - Yeah.
沒錯
I'll get it, I'll get it. I'll get it.
我來處理就好，我處理!
Anything?
有什麼嗎？
No, I'm still on hold.
沒有，還是忙線
Oh, look how happy this fucking guy is.
看那傻×多開心
Have you ever witnessed a moment with that much heat?
你見沒見過他這麼high？
I mean, white-hot heat, bro!
我是說，這麼high
No, it was pretty intense.
沒有，剛剛真是有夠勁爆
Yeah!
耶！
STU: Yeah, it's actually an emergency.
事情很急
He has a thick Asian accent.
那人有口濃重的亞洲音
I totally get it...
我知道了
...but this is a highly unusual circumstance and...
但是現在情況很緊急而且…
Okay. All right.
好吧
It's an escort service.
只是個負責搞三陪的
They're not gonna tell us shit.
沒什麼線索
Maybe an escort would.
找個三陪女怎樣？
- You still have her number? - Yeah, but...
-你還有那誰（醉後大丈夫1）的電話？-是，不過…
...it'd be pretty awkward.
那樣很遜好咩
It's all we got.
我們只能找她了
She smiled at me again, from inside the shop.
她又對我笑了，從店裡面
Ha, ha. This is the best day of my life.
哈哈，今天是我這輩子最屌的一天
[DOORBELL RINGS]
ALL: Hey!
嘿！
Oh, my God, you guys.
天啊，是你們
It's been so long.
都過了這麼久了
- Come in, come in. - Thank you.
-進來，進來-謝謝你
- You look great. - So do you! You're pregnant.
-你看起來不錯啊-你也是啊，你懷孕了
I feel so fat.
我只是胖了
Oh, please.
拜託
Do you guys mind taking your shoes off? I'm a germ freak.
你們能把鞋脫了嗎？我有點潔癖
- Yeah, sure. - Of course.
-好吧-當然
Alan.
艾倫
Alan, what are you doing?
艾倫，你在幹嘛？
ALAN: Sorry.
對不起
- Wow, you have a great house. JADE: - Thank you.
-你房子真不錯-謝謝
I got married a year ago to a surgeon.
我去年嫁給了個外科醫生
- Another doctor, can you believe it? - Another doctor.
-又是一個醫生哦-哦
His name's Jeff. You guys would love him.
他叫傑夫，你們會喜歡他的
Tyler, say hi to Mommy's friends.
泰勒，跟媽咪的朋友們問聲好
Hi.
嗨
- Hey. - Hey.
嗨！
Wait, is that the baby?
等等，那是那個小孩咩（醉後大丈夫1）？
JADE: Yeah, time flies, huh?
是啊，時光飛逝啊，對嗎？
STU: Wow.
哇
Jade is there a place we could talk that's a little bit more private?
能找個私密點的地方好聊天嗎？
Let's go in the kitchen. You guys want coffee?
去廚房吧，想喝咖啡嗎？
Perfect.
太好了
Hey. you coming?
你來嗎？
Is it okay if I go say hello to the little guy?
我能去跟那小傢伙說聲嗨嗎？
Of course.
當然
Nice stuff.
東西不錯
Thanks. Jeff bought it for me.
謝謝，傑夫買給我的
Jeff. Who's that, your fake dad?
傑夫是誰？不是你爸爸？
Your name was Carlos once.
你以前叫卡洛斯
Did you know that?
你知道嗎？
No.
不知道
Well, it was.
這是真的
And, frankly, it suits you better.
說實話，你還是叫卡洛斯好聽
Okay.
好吧
Do you remember me?
還記得我嗎？
No.
不記得了
Are you my real dad?
你是我爸爸？
Yes.
沒錯
I don't know. You gotta understand, I've been out of that world a few years now.
我不懂，我不幹那行很久了
Yeah, of course. We totally get that.
我們知道
I mean, Jeff knows everything and he's cool, but...
我的意思是，傑夫知道我的過去，他沒說什麼，只是…
We're just asking if you can call around...
我們只是問問你知不知道附近…
...just find out if anybody might know where he is.
的人知不知道周在哪裡
We could really use your help.
我們真的需要你的?明
You used to love it when I would carry you around.
你以前很喜歡我背著你走來走去
Sometimes I can still feel your little head on my chest.
有時我還會覺得你的頭靠在我的胸口
So do you like this new Jeff guy?
你喜歡這個叫傑夫的人嗎？
Yeah, he's nice.
喜歡，他人很好
My dad was nice too. We did everything together.
我爸也是個好人，我們什麼都一起做
He was my life partner, heh.
他是我生活的伴侶，哈
I really let him down.
可我讓他失望了
Okay. Wow.
好吧
Just trust me, you don't want to go over there, okay? Not this one.
相信我，你不會想去那裡的好嗎？
I love you too.
我也愛你
She says there's this crazy Chinese guy...
她說這個瘋狂的中國佬…
...and he's holed up in the penthouse suite of Caesars Palace.
在凱撒行宮的頂樓包間裡
There's girls going in and out, drugs everywhere...
妹子們進進出出，滿地的藥…
It sounds like a bad scene.
聽起來屌爆了
PHIL: Hey, Alan?
嘿，艾倫？
We gotta go.
我們得走了
I gotta go, little man.
我要走了，小夥子
It was great talking to you.
跟你聊天很屌
High five.
擊個掌
- It's great to see you. - You too, Jade.
-見到你真好-我也是
- Thanks so much for your help. - Yeah.
-謝謝你幫忙-耶
That's a great kid you got there.
你的孩子真好人
He is the best.
他是最棒的
TYLER: Alan.
艾倫
Oh, hold on. I have something for you.
等等，我有東西要給你
Perfect.
完美了
Oh, please.
拜託
I'll see you around, Carlos.
回頭見，卡洛斯
[PHONE RINGS]
- Yeah. STU: - We got him.
是我，斯圖，我們找到周了
- Great. Where is he? STU: - Caesars Palace.
-好的，他在哪裡？-凱撒行宮
Change of plans. Tell him we're going to Vegas.
調頭，我們去拉斯維加斯
I'm on my way.
我現在過去
There's a spot just outside of town.
城外有個地方
(OVER PHONE) I'll text you the details. Be there at 6 a.m.
我一會發短信告訴你詳細地址，6點見
And make sure the little fucker's tied up.
把那傢伙綁了來見我
We don't have him.
我們還沒抓到他
Hey, Marshall, it's Phil.
嘿，馬歇爾，是菲爾
Maybe Stu wasn't clear.
可能斯圖沒說清楚
We don't actually have Chow, we just know where he is.
我們沒抓到後，只是知道他在哪裡而已
Yeah, and we were hoping that you and your guys...
我們是希望你的人…
- ...could go to Caesars and get him. - I don't give a fuck what you were hoping.
能過來把他抓走-我不管你們想什麼
(OVER PHONE) The deal is you bring Chow to me.
說好了你們帶周來見我
- Oh, fuck. - 6 a.m. Or your friend is dead.
-幹-5點來，不然我就爆了道格的頭
Shit.
幹
STU: Oh, God.
天啊
This place gives me the chills.
我來過這地方
I know, right?
我知道
It's great to be back.
能回來真好
- So many good memories. - Are you kidding me?
-太多美好的回憶了-你他媽的在逗我？
Okay, so here's the deal:
好的，計畫是這樣的
You need a key just to get onto his floor.
你得有鑰匙才能到周那層樓
And then once you're there, he's got security posted at the door.
而且他的保安還在門口守著
It's ridiculous.
真滑稽
Let me guess, that's him?
讓我猜猜，那是他？
PHIL: Yep. The one with the strobe lights.
沒錯，頂樓那金光閃閃那間就是了!
I got an idea.
有辦法了
But you're not gonna like it.
你們一定會嚇尿的
It's not gonna work.
這行不通
Not with that fucking attitude.
你這態度就不行
You know this whole place is made out of marbles?
你知不知道這裡是拿大理石做的？
Come on. Go, go, go.
來吧，快
PHIL: After we stick Chow, Alan and I are gonna take him down through the lobby.
找到周後，艾倫和我會把他帶到大堂
Be waiting in valet. Engine running, ready to go.
在車裡等著，別熄火
Are you sure about this?
你確定？
Give me the Demerol.
把杜米諾給我
See you in 20 minutes.
20分鐘後見
STU: - Hey, Phil? - Yeah?
-嘿，菲爾？-耶？
STU: Don't die.
別死了
[RAKIM MAYERS' "F""KIN' PROBLEMS" PLAYING ON STEREO]
PHIL: All right.
好吧
Are you ready to do this?
你準備好了嗎？
Yeah.
耶
Wait, what are we doing?
等等，我們在幹嘛？
Holy shit.
幹林蛤仔
PHIL: We're gonna climb down...
我們要爬下去
...and then it's about an 8-foot drop to the balcony.
到陽臺那兒得有8英尺高
- All right? - Yeah.
-好了嗎？-耶
No, you spit in your own hand.
你自己吐
Oh, yeah.
好吧
[ALAN SNORTING]
[CONTINUES SNORTING]
Dry desert air.
空氣太乾了
- Alan, it's fine. You don't need it. - Okay.
-沒事的艾倫，你不需要這樣-好吧
Oh, God.
天啊
- Unh! - Careful!
-啊！-小心！
- Phil! - I'm all right.
-菲爾！-我沒事
I'm okay!
我沒事！
- Hey, Phil. - What's wrong?
-嘿，菲爾-怎麼了？
Hold on a second.
等一會兒
- What? - Hold on!
-啥？-等一會兒！
Like, kick yourself out a little bit.
你晃出來點兒
Alan.
艾倫
- Stay still! - Alan!
-別動-艾倫！
[SHUTTER CLICKS]
Did you get it?
拍到了咩？
No. Hold on.
沒有，等等
[SHUTTER CLICKS]
Ha, that's cool, ha-ha-ha.
哈，拍到了
Oh! Fuck me!
喔，我死定了!
ALAN: Everything all right?
一切還好？
It's okay!
沒事
It's all right!
都好！
I got it! Whoa.
我成功了！
Are you okay?
你好嗎？
[RAKIM MAYERS' "F""KIN' PROBLEMS" CONTINUES PLAYING ON STEREO]
Alan, it's your turn.
到你了，艾倫
That's it.
沒錯
Phil, I can't. I can't.
我不行了，菲爾
PHIL: Come on.
來吧
[ALAN WHIMPERING]
[ALAN SCREAMS]
PHIL: Whoa!
哇
Alan, you all right?
艾倫，你還好吧？
Phil, call Security!
叫保安，菲爾！
- I think it's slipping! PHIL: - Just hold on!
-我要滑下去了-抓緊了！
Oh! God!
天啊
- You need to calm down. - I'm slipping, Phil!
-你得放鬆-我在滑，菲爾！
Oh! Fuck!
幹！
Oh, shit! You okay?
幹！你還好嗎？
Help!
救命！
Oh, no.
不
I'm gonna die, Phil.
我要死了
No, you're fine. Just...
你沒事，就…
Drop down to me.
跳下來我接著你
ALAN: No chance.
別鬧了
I'm good up here.
我在這上面很好
Alan, you can do this. I'll catch you.
艾倫你可以的，我會接住你的
Just...
就…
...let go.
跳吧
That's it. That's it. Just drop straight down.
就這樣，直著跳下來
But don't push off.
別往前跳
No!
不！
- Oh, God! - Come here!
-天啊！-到這兒來！
Holy fuck!
他媽的！
You okay?
你還好咩？
Yeah.
嗯
Shit. Oh, fuck.
幹
I almost died, Phil.
我差點死了
Come on. I wasn't gonna let you go. You're my boy.
拜託，我是不會讓你死的，我愛你
And you're my man.
我也愛你
Alan, what are you doing? Alan.
你幹嘛呢，艾倫？
Okay.
好吧
Let's go get this fucker.
我們去抓周那個混蛋
[BLACK SABBATH'S "N.l. B." PLAYING OVER STEREO]
Hey!
嘿！
Have you seen my...?
你們有沒有見到我的……
Huh?
哈？
ALAN: Phil!
菲爾！
Motherfuckers!
王八蛋！
PHIL: Grab the gun!
搶他的槍！
- Oh, fuck! ALAN: - Phil!
幹！菲爾！
PHIL: Oh.
哦
Phil, you okay?
菲爾你還好嗎？
PHIL: Chow!
周！
Chow!
[GRUNTS]
Chow, open the fucking door!
開他媽的的門，周！
Fuck.
幹
[GIRLS SCREAMING]
PHIL: Chow, stop.
別鬧，周
You motherfuckers!
你們王八蛋
Leslie, get down from there! Please! You're gonna hurt yourself!
下來吧，周，你會受傷的
Nothing hurts Chow.
才怪
I am invisible!
我是隱形的
It's "invincible," and you're not. You're just out of your fucking mind.
是"戰無不勝吧"吧，而且你並不是! 你只是瘋了
Now get down from there before you die!
在弄死你自己前快點從那兒下來
Die?
死？
How do you kill what's already dead? Heh-heh-heh.
我都死了你們還怎麼殺我？哈哈哈
Oh, fuck!
幹！
PHIL: Holy...
幹你…
CHOW: Woo-hoo!
喔！
[PHONE RINGS]
- Hey. You okay? PHIL: - No.
嘿，你好嗎？-不好
Look up.
往上看
[STU GASPS]
What the fuck is that?
那他媽是啥？
PHIL: That's Chow! STU: What?
是周！-啥？
Follow him.
跟著他
CHOW: Woo-hoo!
哇！
Whoo!
[LAUGHING]
I love cocaine!
我愛可卡因！
Out of the way!
快走開！
[PEOPLE SCREAMING]
How did this happen?
這是怎麼了？
PHIL: We had him trapped, and then he jumped!
我們把他困住了，結果他跑了
He's out of his fucking mind!
那哥們瘋了！
CHOW: I'm out of my fucking mind!
我瘋了！
[CHOW LAUGHING]
Wow.
哇
So beautiful.
真美
PHIL: Stu, do not lose him.
別跟丟了，斯圖
STU: I'm trying.
我在努力
Whoa!
哇！
[STU SIGHS]
Oh, shit.
喔，幹！
CHOW (SINGING): I believe I can fly
I believe I can touch the sky
Think about it every night and day
We gotta pack up all this gold. We're taking it with us.
我們把這些金條帶走
Talk to me, Stu.
告訴我情況，斯圖
I got him.
我找到他了
Ha, ha. I got him!
哈哈，我找到他了
Oh, shit!
幹！
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
哇，哇，哇
Shit.
幹
Fuck! I lost him!
幹！跟丟了
Don't tell me that. You can't lose him!
別鬧，怎麼可能跟丟了？
STU: This is so much harder than you realize, Phil.
這比你想的難好咩？菲爾
I'm just a dentist!
我只是個看牙的
No, Stu, you're a fucking doctor. Now go get him.
才不，斯圖，你他媽的是個醫生，接著跟
Where the fuck did he go?
他他媽的去哪了？
CHOW: Fuck me!
我幹！
I should have thought this through!
當初真得好好想想
Shit!
幹！
[CHOW GRUNTS]
Move!
滾開！
- Aah! - Stu?
啊！-斯圖？
- Chow? - Stop the fucking car!
-周？-快停車！
PHIL: - Stu. - I can't! The pedal is stuck!
斯圖-停不了，踏板卡住了
- What? PHIL: - Stu?
啥？-斯圖？
[CHOW SCREAMING]
STU: I can't see! - Stop, motherfucker!
我看不到了！-快停車，王八蛋！
STU: Get off! CHOW: Pull over!
拿開你的傘！-停車！
STU: It won't stop! CHOW: Aah!
聽不了了！-啊！
Get off the car!
滾開！
I can't see anything!
我什麼都看不到！
Ha-ha-ha. We're gonna die finally.
哈哈哈，我們要同歸於盡了
[CAR HORN HONKING]
[BOTH SCREAMING]
[CHOW LAUGHING]
STU: Holy shit.
幹
PHIL: Stu? Stu, what happened?
斯圖？怎麼了？
Stu, what's going on?
斯圖，怎麼了？
STU: We had an accident, and I think he's dead.
出事了，周要死了
PHIL: Wait, what?
啥，啥？
I think I killed him.
我想我殺了他
Holy shit.
幹
He's not moving.
他不動了
PHIL: Oh, fuck.
幹
STU: Mr. Chow?
周？
Chow.
[CHOW COUGHING]
Stuart?
斯圖？
He's alive. He's okay.
他活著，他沒事
PHIL: Oh, great.
太好了
Put him in the limo and come get us. We'll meet you at valet.
把他放上車然後來找我們
Yeah, okay.
好，好
Stu.
斯圖
That was some ride, huh, pal?
真像玩命關頭，哈？
Yeah, it was pretty wild.
那是
I can't feel my nuts.
我要死了
Would you rub them and make sure they okay?
你摸摸我的蛋看它們還好嗎？
It's over, Leslie.
別鬧了，周
CHOW: Wait.
等等
Let's make a deal.
我們可以談談
Want Chow to blow your dick?
想讓我幫你吹咩？
Come on, Stu.
別鬧了，斯圖
I could be a good wife to you.
我會把你吹的爽爽的
STU: No more deals. - No, wait!
-談個屁-等等！
Let's put the bags in the back seat.
把袋子放到後座上
Trunk's full.
後車箱滿了
[THUMPING FROM TRUNK]
CHOW: Hey, guys? I'm feeling better now.
嘿，我現在好多了
All right, it's the next exit, then four miles straight into the desert.
好，下個路口出去，直著開4英里進沙漠
CHOW: Tell you what:
聽著
Let me out, we split the gold four ways. Everyone wins.
讓我出去，金子咱們分四份，大家都爽
[THUMPING FROM TRUNK]
CHOW: Marshall gonna kill me!
馬歇爾會殺了我的
My blood will be on your hands!
你們都是幫兇！
You want Chow's ghost haunting you for rest of your life, Stu?
我做鬼都不會放過你的，斯圖
Floating over you while you make fuck on your wife?
掛你頭上看著你和你老婆啪啪啪
He's not gonna kill you, Chow! He just wants his gold back!
馬歇爾不會的，他只想要他的金子
CHOW: It's gone. I blew the first 20 million in Bangkok.
金子沒了，我全花了
- That's why I had to get the other half. - Enough, Chow! It's over!
-所以我才回來要剩下的-夠了，周，都結束了
CHOW: You motherfucker!
你們王八蛋！
When I get out of this, I'm gonna rip out your fucking lungs!
我要死不了你們就完蛋了！
You hear me? You're dead! You're all dead!
聽到嗎？你們完蛋了，完蛋了！
I didn't mean that.
我不是這意思
Chow loses temper sometimes.
我有時會發飆
Please. I need help.
求你了，我需要幫助
I know that now.
我知道
That's the exit.
那個路口出
PHIL: They're here.
他們到了
Alan, they're coming, grab the last bag.
艾倫，他們來了，把周拿出來
CHOW: Please, Alan.
求你了，艾倫
Doug!
道格！
Step away from the bags. Let's go!
離那袋子遠點
We good?
沒事了吧？
- It's all there. I promise. MARSHALL: - Not exactly.
-都在那裡，我保證-不全是
I'm still missing the original half.
原來那一半呢？
But, no, that's all we have. Chow said he blew the other half in Bangkok.
我們只找到這些，周說那一半在曼谷全花了
Where is he?
他人呢？
He's in the trunk.
後車箱裡
Deal's a deal.
我遵守承諾
- Doug. - Give me the keys.
-道格-鑰匙給我
What are you gonna do with Chow?
你們要對周做什麼？
I just wanna talk to him.
只是聊聊
Move.
滾開
You all right?
你還好嗎？
What the fuck?
搞什麼？
End of conversation.
聊完了
Why would you do that?
你為什麼這麼做？
Leslie Chow is madness.
他是條瘋狗
You don't talk to madness.
瘋狗不會說話的，聊什麼
If you're lucky, you trap it in the trunk of your limo and you kill it.
你們把瘋狗困在車裡然後殺了它
You did a great thing tonight.
就是做了一件大好事
You should feel good about this.
你們應該感到開心
What the fuck? You think this is a fucking game?
搞什麼？你覺得這好玩咩？
Don't, don't, don't!
不，不，不！
Oh, shit!
幹！
Toodle-loo, motherfuckers.
哈哈哈，王八蛋們
Chow.
周
Chow. Chow, wait.
周，周，等等
Oh, now you wanna talk, blue eyes?
現在你們想聊了哈？
No more silent treatment?
想理我了哈？
Leslie. No.
周，不要
Stay out of this, fatty.
你別管，肥仔
No, Leslie.
不要，周
You shoot Phil, you gotta go through me.
你要射菲爾，就得先射我
What?
啥？
- Alan. - Quiet.
-艾倫-別吵
I'm in a stare-off.
我在和他對視
Today you all live.
今天你們不死
Because one of you was a friend.
是我給艾倫面子
Alan, what did you do?
艾倫，你幹嘛了？
I unlocked the latch between the back seat and the trunk.
我把後座和後備箱的閂打開了
And left him his gun?
還給了他把槍？
Yeah, I didn't think it all the way through.
是啊，我一路上都沒想到
He gave Chow a fighting chance.
他給了老週一個機會
That's all I ever need.
這正是我想要的
CHOW: Fat fuck.
死肥豬
It's never easy, is it?
不容易啊，是不是？
No one wants to see that.
沒人想看見這樣
Except for me, but I was born bad.
除了我，我天生是個壞蛋
Hold on. I have something for you.
等等，我有東西給你
For your loyalty.
因為你對我好
- Oh, no, I don't want this, Mr. Chow. - Okay, give it back, then. Come on.
-不，我不想要這些，周-那好，還來
Quick! Before Stu smells it.
快點，別讓斯圖知道
I don't want it either, Chow.
我也不想要
Oh, please. Like a squirrel doesn't want a nut.
別鬧了，人還能不為財死？
[CHOW LAUGHING]
It funny because he's Jewish.
那他一定是個猶太人
Don't you get it?
你懂嗎？
Goddamn it.
幹
Okay, go on. Get out of here, all of you.
好吧，都走吧
Hey, chubster, I'll call you in a week. We'll get together.
回頭我還會聯繫你的
No, Leslie, we can't be friends anymore.
別了，周，我不帶你玩了
What?
啥？
You're not good for me. It's not healthy.
你一點都不健康
Alan, you're not thinking straight.
艾倫，你在想什麼？
Let's just talk tomorrow.
明天再聊吧
Leslie, you're one of the coolest and nicest guys I've ever met.
周，你是我見過的最酷最屌的人
And you're smart and you're funny and everybody loves you.
你很聰明，很有趣，大家都愛你
Alan. What is this?
什麼意思？
When we get together, bad things happen and people get hurt.
我們要在一起事情就變壞了，還有人會死
Yeah, that's the point. It's funny.
說的沒錯啊，這樣不好玩咩？
Well, I've gotta make some changes in my life, and this is one of them.
我不能這樣下去了，我得改變
I'm sorry.
對不起
Farewell, Leslie Chow.
後會有期，周
You're cold as ice.
你們真冷酷
Shotgun.
完了
[PHIL SIGHS]
Everybody okay?
大家還好？
Yeah.
嗯
PHIL: Alan, you okay?
艾倫，你呢？
Yeah.
嗯
Good. Let's go home.
好的，回家吧
Jesus Christ.
老天爺
You know what, guys?
知道嗎？
You can go ahead without me. There's something I need to do.
我得去處理點私人事務
Do you even know how to get home?
知道怎麼回家咩？
Of course I do. I'm a grown man.
當然，我不小了
I'll ask a stranger.
會問路人的
Good luck, Alan.
祝你好運，艾倫
We'll see you soon.
回頭見
Did you know that just a couple blocks from here...
你知不知道離這裡幾個街區…
...there's a place that looks exactly like Paris, France?
有個地方看起來很像法國巴黎？
I can't remember what it's called, but it's supposed to be magnificent.
我記不起來那裡叫什麼了，但絕對屌
It's called Paris Hotel and Casino, and it is magnificent.
那裡叫巴黎賭場旅館，確實屌
Yeah, that's it.
沒錯
Well, I'd like to take you to dinner there. Tonight.
我想請你去那吃晚餐，今晚
Oh, sorry. No can do.
不行
Oh, well...
好吧
I'm banned from the casino for life.
我這輩子不能再去賭場了
Plus 10 years.
外加10年
I took Mom there for her birthday, played a little blackjack.
上次我媽過生日我帶她去那兒玩了21點
She split 10s.
她分了兩張10分的牌
- Oh. - I may have overreacted.
-哦-我反應過度了
They said it was abuse of an elderly.
他們說這有點虐待老年人的意思
Ha, ha. I've done that.
哈哈，我也這麼做過
Heh. Right? Whatever.
是嗎？無所謂了
I can't go back there.
我不能再回去了
But, uh...
但是，呃…
...Golden Nugget has the best prime rib in town, if that's...
Golden Nuggest有最棒的羊排，如果…
Well, that sounds glorious.
聽起來很屌
I'll send for you at 8:00.
8點見
Is that it?
就這樣？
[BOTH CHUCKLE]
I saw it once in a pornography.
我在黃片裡見過這一幕
Oh.
哦
It's a nice gesture.
不錯的姿勢
But maybe we should wait.
可或許我們該等等
Oh. Okay. Yeah, yeah.
好吧，好吧
[CHUCKLES]
I'll see you at 8.
8點見
You look great, Alan.
你看起來真不錯，艾倫
What do you think? Hat or no hat?
戴不戴帽子？
Uh...
呃…
- Hat. For sure. - Oh, yeah. Okay.
-帽子得戴-好
Wow. Who's this guy?
這是？
The vest and the cane? I love it.
穿背心的現在拿起了手杖？屌爆了
Thank you. Cassie picked it out for me.
謝謝你，凱西給我挑的
You look like Mr. Peanut.
圓滾滾的
Yeah, I know, right? That's what I was going for.
我知道，這是我一直努力的方向
- Maybe we'll just lose it. - Yeah.
-還是別了吧-耶
Hey, Alan, I was just talking to Cassie. She's an amazing woman.
嘿艾倫，我剛有跟凱西聊，她是個很屌的女人
Oh, thank you for saying that. She is an amazing woman.
謝謝你這麼說，她確實很屌
I find her much better than your wives.
我覺得她比你老婆屌多了
Aw. That's sweet.
哦，不錯…
Which reminds me. Um, we need to talk. Doug?
這讓我想到，呃，道格， 能聊會兒嗎？
All right, listen, fellas.
好吧，我聽著呢
Now that I'm getting married, I'm gonna be spending a lot more time with Cassandra.
現在我要結婚了，我得多花時間在我那位身上了
- Yeah. It's the way it should be. - No, you slow your roll, Phil, okay?
-就該這樣-不，菲爾你別說話先好嗎？
There's more.
我還有話說
And you're not gonna like this part.
而且你不會喜歡我接下來要說的
I must resign from the wolf pack.
我不再是狼友了
Wow, that's a big step, Alan.
哇，這可是件大事，艾倫
ALAN: I know.
我知道
But she's my soul mate.
她是我的靈魂伴侶
And my new best friend.
和我新的最好的朋友
Plus, she lets me mount her...
還有，她還能讓我騎她…
...which relaxes me.
這讓我感覺輕鬆多了
Oh, my God.
天啊
Alan, maybe never say that part again.
這話就不要說了，艾倫
Chillax, Doug, we're all adults here.
放鬆，道格，都不小了
I know you mount my sister. I've seen it. Many times.
我知道你也騎過我姐，我看到過的，好幾次呢
What?
啥？
Alan, you are the best.
艾倫，你是最棒的
The point is:
關鍵是
You need to let me go.
你們就別管我了
You in particular.
尤其是你
I can't be your hero anymore.
我不能再罩著你了
Okay. Sure.
好吧，好吧
Having said all that...
說了這麼多…
...I still would like to get together on Tuesdays for bowling...
我還是想每週二咱聚在一起打保齡球
...and alternating Sundays for general horseplay.
每隔一個週六去大鬧一場
- How about we play all that by ear? - Alan, it's time.
-別定時間了，不如隨意發揮吧-是時候了，艾倫
Here we go.
走吧
Ready?
準備好了？
[SIGHS]
I'm ready.
好了
[PHIL GRUNTING]
What the fuck?
搞什麼？
Oh.
哦
[G LASS SHATTERS]
[STU LAUGHING]
[LAUGHING]
Oh, my God.
天啊
You guys.
你們
We're so crazy.
我們太瘋狂了
I'm wearing women's underwear. Ha-ha-ha.
我穿著女人的內衣，哈哈哈
Oh, my God. Ha-ha-ha.
天啊，哈哈哈
Stu, don't freak out, but you need to look down.
斯圖，別怕，往下看
What?
啥？
Oh, my God!
天啊
[CASSIE CONTINUES LAUGHING]
[YELLS]
PHIL: Ho-ho-ho. - Aah!
哈哈哈哈
[CASSIE CONTINUES LAUGHING]
PHIL: Oh, fuck!
幹！
I have boobies now!
哥有胸啦！
Holy shit!
幹
STU: It's not funny!
這一點都不好笑
Alan, what did you do?
艾倫，你做了什麼？
What did you do, Alan?
艾倫？
The wedding cake.
結婚蛋糕
It was from Leslie.
是周送的
[GLASS BREAKING]
Oh, my God.
天啊
We had a sick night, bitches. Heh-heh-heh.
一夜瘋癲哈，賤人們，哈哈哈
[SCREAMING]
Uploaded by Vajira Lasantha (vajee555)
簡體字幕製作：Gercy
雙語字幕製作：Reinhot